<?xml version="1.0"?>
<release version="4.2.1">
  <version>4.2.1</version>
  <date>2002-05-13</date>
  <stage>stable</stage>
  <source>
    <file compression="tar.gz">
      <name>Source (tar.gz)</name>
      <filename>php-4.2.1.tar.gz</filename>
      <date>2001-01-01</date>
      <md5/>
    </file>
  </source>
  <announcements>
    <announcement lang="en">[ [Version Fran&#xE7;aise](/releases/4_2_1_fr.php) ]

Bugfix release
--------------

 This bug fix release solves a few bugs found in PHP 4.2.0. PHP 4.2.1 includes the following fixes:

- Fix for the MySQL extension not be able to connect to a MySQL server.
- Fix for a crash in the COM extension when using an outproc server.
- Fix for SID logic in the session extension.
- Fixes for the mbstring extension, including SJIS directory name handling and mb_output_buffer().
- Fix for a bug in socket_select() that could cause unexpected behavior when using a statement like $w = $e = array($sock);
- Almost full DOM compliance for the domxml extension, and fixes for several functions.
- Safe_mode checks for show_source(), parse_ini_file() and rmdir().

 For a full list of changes in PHP 4.2.1, see the [ChangeLog](/ChangeLog-4.php#4.2.1).

Compatibility
-------------

 PHP 4.2.1 also has improved (but still experimental) support for Apache version 2. We do **not** recommend that you use this in a production environment, but feel free to test it and report bugs to the [bug system](http://bugs.php.net).

External variables
------------------

 We would also like to attend you on a big change in PHP 4.2.0 concerning variable handling. **External variables (from the environment, the HTTP request, cookies or the web server) are no longer registered in the global scope by default.** The preferred method of accessing these external variables is by using the new Superglobal arrays, introduced in PHP 4.1.0. More information about this change:

- [PHP Manual: Predefined variables](/manual/en/language.variables.predefined.php)
- [The PHP 4.1.0 release announcement](/release_4_1_0.php)
- [Thomas Oertli's article on secure programming in PHP](http://www.zend.com/zend/art/art-oertli.php)</announcement>
  </announcements>
  <changes>
    <modules>
      <module id="major update of domxml. new functions, better dom compliance and bug fixes">
        <change>
          <description>Changed the old $node-&gt;append_child() to $node-&gt;append_sibling() since the new append_child() behaves correctly (= W3C standard).</description>
          <references/>
        </change>
        <change>
          <description>Added domxml functions:</description>
          <references/>
        </change>
        <change>
          <description>Fixed a segfault in domxml_unlink().</description>
          <references/>
        </change>
        <change>
          <description>Added formatting option to domxml_dump_mem().</description>
          <references/>
        </change>
      </module>
    </modules>
  </changes>
  <windows_builds/>
  <tags/>
</release>
