<?xml version="1.0"?>
<release version="4.4.1">
  <version>4.4.1</version>
  <date>2005-10-31</date>
  <sources>
    <source>
      <name>Source (tar.gz)</name>
      <filename>php-4.4.1.tar.gz</filename>
      <date>2020-01-07</date>
      <md5/>
    </source>
    <source>
      <name>Source (tar.bz2)</name>
      <filename>php-4.4.1.tar.bz2</filename>
      <date>2020-01-07</date>
      <md5/>
    </source>
  </sources>
  <announcements>
    <announcement lang="en">PHP 4.4.1. Release Announcement


The PHP Development Team would like to announce the immediate release of [PHP 4.4.1](/downloads.php).

This is a bug fix release, which addresses some security problems too. The security issues that this release fixes are:

- Fixed a Cross Site Scripting ([XSS](http://www.cgisecurity.com/articles/xss-faq.shtml)) vulnerability in [phpinfo](/phpinfo)() that could lead f.e. to cookie exposure, when a phpinfo() script is accidently left on a production server.
- Fixed multiple safe_mode/open_basedir bypass vulnerabilities in ext/curl and ext/gd that could lead to exposure of files normally not accessible due to safe_mode or open_basedir restrictions.
- Fixed a possible $GLOBALS overwrite problem in file upload handling, extract() and import_request_variables() that could lead to unexpected security holes in scripts assumed secure. (For more information, see [here](http://www.hardened-php.net/globals-problem)).
- Fixed a problem when a request was terminated due to memory_limit constraints during certain [parse_str](/parse_str)() calls. In some cases this can result in register_globals being turned on.
- Fixed an issue with trailing slashes in allowed basedirs. They were ignored by open_basedir checks, so that specified basedirs were handled as prefixes and not as full directory names.
- Fixed an issue with calling [virtual](/virtual)() on Apache 2. This allowed bypassing of certain configuration directives like safe_mode or open_basedir.
- Updated to the latest pcrelib to fix a possible integer overflow vulnerability announced in [CAN-2005-2491](http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CAN-2005-2491).

This release also fixes 35 other defects, where the most important is the the fix that removes a notice when passing a by-reference result of a function as a by-reference value to another function. (Bug #[33558](http://bugs.php.net/33558)).

 For a full list of changes in PHP 4.4.1, see the [ChangeLog](/ChangeLog-4.php#4.4.1).</announcement>
  </announcements>
  <changes>
    <modules/>
  </changes>
  <tags/>
</release>
